omax.com 2019-07-12

# OMAX Privacy Policy | Water Jet Cutting Machine

Privacy Statement Effective as of May 23, 2018.

OMAX Corporation is committed to protecting the privacy of your information. This Privacy Statement describes the information collection practices for our company.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [omax@omax.com](mailto:omax@omax.com).

## **1\. Data Collection Covered**

This privacy statement covers customer data collected from our websites ([www.omax.com](https://www.omax.com/), [www.protomax.com](https://www.protomax.com/), [community.protomax.com](https://community.protomax.com/), [support.omax.com](https://support.omax.com/), [marketplace.omax.com](https://marketplace.omax.com/), [global.omax.com](https://global.omax.com/)), tradeshows and events, email, phone and face-to-face interactions with OMAX.

OMAX Corporation web sites may contain links to other Web sites. OMAX is not responsible for the information practices or the content of such other Web sites. The Company encourages you to review the privacy statements of other Web sites to understand their information practices.

## **2\. Personal Information Collected**

Customer data collected varies depending on the source of collection and the intended use of the information. For example, website information requests require your name, email, phone number or zip code where regionally applicable. Company name and website address are optional. Some support areas require your OMAX account number, machine serial number(s), and your business name.

The Company uses the information collected from you to respond to your informational, technical, and support requests and to communicate offers or information we believe you may find of interest. OMAX will never sell your personal information to any third parties. OMAX may forward your information to an OMAX distributor if the Company believes the distributor would be a more suitable party to answer your request. OMAX may also forward your information to our financing partners based on your request.

As you navigate the Company's Web sites, OMAX may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons ("Web Site Navigational Information"). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, and the actions you take on the Company's Web sites (such as the Web pages viewed and the links clicked).

## **3\. Use of Information Collected By OMAX**

The Company uses your information to answer your requests. For example, if you fill out a "Contact Us" Web form, the Company will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in OMAX products.

The Company may also use your information for marketing purposes. For example, the Company may use information you provide to contact you to send you information regarding the Company and its partners, such as information about products, promotions or events.

OMAX uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve the Company's Web sites. The Company may also use Web Site Navigational Information in combination with your information to provide you personalized information about the Company.

## **4\. Web Site Navigational Information**

OMAX.com uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons, to collect information as you navigate the Company's Web sites ("Web Site Navigational Information". This section describes the types of Web Site Navigational Information the Company may collect and how the Company may use this information.

### **Cookies  **

OMAX.com uses cookies to make interactions with the Company's Web sites easy and meaningful. When you visit one of the Company's Web sites, OMAX servers send a cookie to your computer. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you. They merely recognize your Web browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to OMAX.com, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening a support area account, or filling out a Web form, you remain anonymous to the Company.

There are two types of cookies: session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you close your browser or turn off your computer.

If you have chosen to identify yourself to on OMAX websites, the Company uses session cookies containing encrypted information to allow the Company to uniquely identify you. Each time you log into our Support area, a session cookie containing an encrypted, unique identifier that is tied to your account is placed in your browser. These session cookies allow the Company to uniquely identify you when you are logged into the Service and to process your online downloads and requests. Session cookies are required to use the website support areas.

OMAX uses persistent cookies that only the Company can read and use to identify browsers that have previously visited the Company's Web sites. When you visit OMAX websites, a unique identifier is associated with a persistent cookie that the Company places on your Web browser. The Company is especially careful about the security and confidentiality of the information stored in persistent cookies. For example, the Company does not store account numbers or passwords in persistent cookies. If you disable your Web browser's ability to accept cookies, you will be able to navigate the Company's Web sites, but you will not be able to successfully use the OMAX.com support area.

OMAX may use information from session and persistent cookies in combination with your provided information to provide you with information about the Company.

### **Web Beacons**

OMAX uses Web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about Customers and Visitors' usage of the Company's Web sites and interaction with emails from the Company. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular Web site tied to the Web beacon, and a description of a Web site tied to the Web beacon. For example, OMAX may place Web beacons in marketing emails that notify the Company when you click on a link in the email that directs you to one of the Company's Web sites. OMAX uses Web beacons to operate and improve the Company's Web sites and email communications.

### **IP Addresses**

When you visit OMAX Web sites, the Company collects your Internet Protocol ("IP") addresses to track and aggregate non-personally identifiable information. For example, OMAX websites use IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Customers and Visitors navigate the Company's Web sites.

### **Third Party Cookies**

From time-to-time, OMAX engages third parties to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from individuals who visit the Company's Web sites. OMAX.com may also use other third-party cookies to track the performance of Company advertisements. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after the Company receives it. This Privacy Statement does not cover the use of third party cookies.

## **5\. Public Forums, Refer a Friend, and Customer Testimonials**

OMAX may provide bulletin boards, communities, forums, blogs ([www.drolsenslab.com](http://www.drolsenslab.com/)), or live chat on the Company's Web sites. Any personally identifiable information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. OMAX is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

OMAX posts a list of Customers and testimonials on the Company's Web sites ("Customer Spotlights, Customer Successes, Customer Testimonials") that contain information such as Customer names and titles. OMAX obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials. 

## **6\. Sharing of Information Collected**

OMAX may share your information with the Company's agents so that these agents can contact Customers and Visitors who have provided contact information on our behalf. OMAX.com may also share your information with the Company's agents to ensure the quality of information provided. OMAX does not share, sell, rent, or trade personally identifiable information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

OMAX reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information of the Company's Customers or Visitors if required by law or if the Company reasonably believes that disclosure is necessary to protect the Company's rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.

## **7\. Communications Preferences**

OMAX offers Customers and Visitors who provide contact information a means to choose how the Company uses the information provided. You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the " unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of the Company's marketing emails. Additionally, you may send a request specifying your communications preferences to [omax@OMAX.com](mailto:omax@OMAX.com). Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with OMAX or OMAX support.

## **8\. Accessing, Correcting, and Deleting Your Personal Information Collected by OMAX**

You may send us an email at [gdpr@omax.com](mailto:gdpr@omax.com) to request access to, changes to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us in connection with any OMAX data collection method. We respond to all such requests, but reserve the right to enforce reasonable limits in cases with legal restrictions and regulatory compliance.

## **9\. Security**

OMAX website-based customer support uses password protected security measures to protect your information from unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and help ensure the appropriate use of your account information. To access the support area your username and password are required. OMAX also implements an advanced security method based on dynamic data and encoded session identifications.

## **10\. Changes to this Privacy Statement**

OMAX reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it.

## **11\. Contacting Us**

Questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of the Company's Web sites should be emailed to [omax@omax.com](mailto:omax@omax.com).
